The West the way it really was!
The Great Northfield Minnesota Raid is a drama,
western film directed by Philip Kaufman.
The gangs of Jesse James and Cole Younger join forces to rob the First National
Bank in Northfield, Minnesota, but things do not go as planned.
Cole Younger, played by Cliff Robertson.
Jesse James, played by Robert Duvall.
Jim Younger, played by Luke Askew.
Clell Miller, played by R.G. Armstrong.
Allen, played by Dana Elcar.
Manning, played by Donald Moffat.
The Great Northfield, Minnesota Raid is a 1972 American
Western film about the James-Younger Gang.
Distributed by Universal Pictures, it was written and directed by Philip
Kaufman in a cinéma vérité style and stars Cliff Robertson.
The film purports to recreate the James-Younger Gang's most infamous escapade, the September 7,
1876 robbery of "the biggest bank west of the Mississippi", in Northfield, Minnesota.
The tone is emotional.